<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-1884-presidential-election</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86053573/1884-07-12/ed-1/seq-1/#words=CLEVELAND+WINS+Grover+Hendricks+Democratic+Convention+Chicago</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CLEVELAND WINS IT. When Pennsylvania returned In tho hall,
and Its chairman announced 42 votes for Cleve
land, another stirring scone Occurred, and the
Cleveland men knowing that this gave them a
majority of thirty over a majority of the votes
cast, they wero enthusiastically eangnlno of
tho result aud cheered llko victors. v hen tho
roll of the states bad been finished and beforo
tho result was announced, a dozen of men
wcro clamoring for recognition from tho chair.
It was evident that tho convention had not
been stampeded for Hendricks. The Clovoland
ranks had stood firm agnlnrt tho flerco and de
termined assault of tho opposition. 
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042460/1884-11-08/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Cock+Crows+Cleveland+Grover+Election+Hendricks</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  THE ELECTION. There c.au no
longer be any question concerning the
actual result of the Presidential election,
Grovcr Cleveland and Thomas A. Heudrlcks
have a majority of 18 in the Electoral Col
lege. It is not worth while for our adversar
rles to claim the electoral vote of the
State of New York. It is absolutely
certain that the returns of the pruper officer!
of election ou the night of the tth of Nnven*
bei showed a decisive plurality of the State
for the electors supporting t levelaud and
llendrickfl. If any different or altered re
turns are now being prepared or are pro
mulgated, they are corrupt falsifications
of the record* of the State of New York, ant}
the men aiding or abetting the making of
such reports are criminals. It is not expect
ed that you will tamely submit to the ma, hl
n itloua <>f such men.
  </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-alaska-gold-rush</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99021999/1890-05-04/ed-1/seq-5/#words=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE GOLD FIELDS OF ALASKA.
  Since the acquisition of Alaska in 1867
public attention In regard to it has boon
mainly directed to the salmon fisheries
in Its waters and to the seal rookeries in
Bohring sea. The value of the country
as a dependency has boon wholly deter
mined by the public from the rental
which the PrlbOlolT Islands yield to the
national treasury. Few references in the
intor\-oning period have boon made by
public journals and in the periodical
literature of the country to the gold-
yielding capabilities of Alaska , or' to the
degree of development already reached.
The truth Is that hundreds of thousands
of intelligent Americans are profoundly
ignorant of the fact that some of the
largest and most profitable gold mining
ontorpribcs within the limits of the
United States are conducted in Alaska.
Gold in variable quantities and under
different conditions has been found in
three principal districts of Alaska the
Juneau and Douglass Island dibtrict , ISO
iriilos northeast of Sltka nnd bordering
Gastcncaux channel , a narrow inlet
which separates Douglass island from
the mainland ; the Sltka dibtrict , the
quarU deposits of which nro found at
Silver Iwy , n narrow , tortuous arm of
the Pacific , indenting BaranolT island ,
nnd in the valley of the Yukon river In
western Alaska. Gold bearing quart/
has albo been found nt Unga island , ono
of the smaller of the Aleutian group , and
SQIUO egort has been made there at de
velopment , but moro of that hereafter.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063615/1897-07-20/ed-1/seq-2/#words=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GOLD FEVER RAGING.
  Port Townsend, Wash., July 19 The ex
cursion steamer Queen has arrived from
Alaska with 170 passengers, principally
tourists. Tho officers of the Queen state
that the merchants and tradesmen in both
Juneau and Sitka are closing their shops
and hastening to the new Eldorado Fifty
business men left Juneau for Daw ton City
on Julv 12, and 130 were to leave on the
16th, two das after the Queen sailed The
officers sa that by tho time tho Queen re
turns to Juneau on her return trip, nine
davs hence, there will not ba an able-bodied
man left in the town. Many men are leav
ing Juneau for tho gold fields without pro
visions or means to buy them
Tho steamer Al Kl balled for Alaska at
midnight. She carries forty horses and 1,000
sheep for Dyca, where they will be land
ed and driven across tho summit to the
Yukon vallei. Stockmen say the sheep
are the finest band ever collected off East
ern Washington ranges. They will be taken
to Circle City and Klondike and slaughter
ed. Any kind of fresh meat there sells at
50 cents per pound.
San Diego, Cal., July 19. An Interesting
letter telling of the recent trip of the
steamer Excelsior to Alaska has been writ
ten by Captain J. F. Hlggins, of the steam
er, to a friend In this city Hesajs.
"The word Klondike means Deer river,
which Is called Reindeer river on the
charts. It empties into tho Yukon fifty
miles abovo tho big river. The geographic
al position of the Junction is 76 degrees 10
minutes north latitude. 139 degrees 50 min
utes west longitude. Ronanza creek dumps
Into Klondike about two miles above the
Yukon. Eldorado is a tributary of the
Bonanza. Ther are numerous other creeks
and tributaries, the main river being 300
miles long The gold so far has been taken
from the Ronanza and Eldorado, both well
named, for the richness of the placers lz
truly marvelous. Eldorado, thirty miles
long. Is staked the whole length and as far
as worked has paid.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-assassination-franz-ferdinand</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88078751/1914-06-30/ed-1/seq-1/#words=archduke+Archduke+Bosnia+Emperor+Ferdinand+FERDINAND+Sarajevo+Servia</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>VICTIMS OF ASSASIN'S BULLETS.
  After making the rounds of the
town hall, which occupied half an
hour, the archduke and tho duchess
startod for the garrison to visit Col
onel Morizzi. the archduke's aid, who
was injured by the bomb explosion
and who had been taUon to tho hospital
wm
Down In Street Of
erjevo ,
In a carrlape after the outrage. As
tif roynl car reached tho corner of
R-,uIolf strpet a man named Gavro
Pr.nzip, who was on the sidewalk,
fired two pistol shots In quick succes
sion at the archduke and the duchess
The man.Avhowas but a short distance
from the car, was a good marksman.
The first shot struck tho Duchess of
Hohenberg low down on the right
side, while the second bullet hit tho
archduke In the neck near the throat
and pierced the jugular vein.
The duchess became immediately
unconscious and fell across the knees
of her husband. The archduke lost
consciousness in a few seconds after
he. was hit. The chauffeur put on full
spce'd and rushed straight to the pal
ace, where an army of surgeons vain
ly tried first aid to the Injured.
Neither the archduke nor the duch
ess gave any sign of life and the only
tblug the head of the hospital could
do was to certify that both were dead.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99063957/1914-07-24/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Archduke+Austria+Bosnia+demand+Demand+demanded+demanding+demands+DEMANDS+Ferdinand+Hungary+Servia+ultimatum</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AUSTRIA DEMANDS PUNISHMENT OF PRICES DEATH. 
  Berlin, July 24. A "world war"
unless Servia complies with the de
mands Austria has mnde upon it, was.
boing predicted todny by diplomats and
military men here.
The Austrian ultimatum was a sequel
to the recent assassinntion of Archduke
Kraneis Ferdinand, Emperor Francis
Joseph's heir, by a Servian student at
Herajevo, Bosnia province.
It was freely asserted at the time
that the killing was the result of a
fot hntohed at Belgrade by a Pan
Hervian organization . with extensive
ramifications in Austria, which has a
largo Servian population in its south
eastern provinces.
It was expected immediately after
the assassination that Austria would
demand an explanation from the Ser
vian government. It delayed so long,
however, that it began to be believed
the emperor was afraid he would preci
pitate a revolt of his own Servian sub
jects if he assumed a belligerent tone.
Late Thursday the Vienna foreign
office suddenly spoke. .Servia was
tilled on, not only to punish those con
concerned in the assassination plot
against Francis Ferdinand, but to sup
press at once the Pan-Servian move
ment. An answer was required by 6 p. m.
Saturday.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
